freeindex.co.uk 2019-06-11

# FreeIndex.co.uk - Privacy Policy

## About this Document

This is the privacy policy for FreeIndex.co.uk (FreeIndex Ltd). It describes how we collect and use the personal data of our users, and business advertisers, and who has access to this information.

## What personal data we collect

When you register on FreeIndex.co.uk, we collect personal information about you. Whether you sign up to FreeIndex as a consumer or a business we collect the following...

  * Your name
  * Your email address
  * Your postcode
  * A password of your choosing.

If you sign-up to advertise your business on FreeIndex, we also collect the following...

  * Your business's address and contact details
  * Your business's status (e.g. Ltd, Sole Trader etc)
  * As you create your business profile on FreeIndex for the purpose of advertising your business, you may also provide other information including a description of your business, opening hours, details of your products and services etc...

The lawful basis for processing this information is to fulfil our contract to you to advertise your business, to allow you to get quotes from businesses or to write reviews on FreeIndex.

We do not store credit card details on our server.

## Cookies

FreeIndex Ltd may set and access basic cookies on your computer as a site user. These cookies are used purely to enhance your user experience and are kept to a minimum. Most cookies are session cookies that expire and are removed when you end your session.

You are free to turn cookies off using your browser settings but certain sections of the site will no longer work without cookies enabled.

We use Google Adsense to provide relevant adverts to our users. Google may set cookies on your computer as part of this provision.

## Who has access to your personal data?

FreeIndex Ltd does not rent, sell, or share any of your personal data with any 3rd parties.

We limit access to personal information about you to FreeIndex employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs.

We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect personal information about you. Any data we collect is securely stored on our UK based database server.

In the case where you write a review of a business on FreeIndex, your name and Locality will be published alongside your review.

In the case where you use our Multiquote service, your name and contact details may be passed onto a maximum of 5 businesses, for the sole purpose of allowing them to fulfil your request.

If you sign-up as a Premium Member your basic contact details are shared with our payment provider (GoCardless) for the purpose of handling the transaction and future direct debits.

## How long do we keep your personal data for?

We retain your personal data for no longer than is necessary for the purpose(s) for which it was provided.

## What do we use your personal data for?

  * To advertise your business on FreeIndex, within search engines and on social media sites
  * To track usage of Freeindex.co.uk
  * To allow us to contact you regarding your activity on FreeIndex.co.uk
  * To allow us to contact you regarding new features and services on FreeIndex.co.uk
  * To provide you with customer support
  * To respond to enquiries, complaints and disputes
  * To investigate, detect and prevent fraud and comply with our legal obligations.

## Your Rights

  * Right to be Informed - (this document)
  * Right of Access - You have the right to request access to the personal data we hold. Please [get in touch](https://www.freeindex.co.uk/contact.htm?enquirytype=data_request) if you would like a copy of the personal data we hold.
  * Right to Erasure - You have the right to be forgotten and have your information removed from FreeIndex. Please [contact us](https://www.freeindex.co.uk/contact.htm?enquirytype=data_request) if you would like your personal data to be deleted.

## Contacting FreeIndex

Please [contact us](https://www.freeindex.co.uk/contact.htm) if you have any queries or issues relating to this policy.

## Changes to this Policy

FreeIndex Ltd may update this policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your Business Listing or account username, or by placing a prominent notice on the site.
